<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><!DOCTYPE course SYSTEM "corpus.dtd"><course id="IKEA_EN" title="IKEA FAQ" lang="EN"><lecture id="IKEA_EN_001" title="IKEA FAQ" date="2014-03-20"><question id="Q4192"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I shop in IKEA?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4283"><answer_text><a_sentence>We want your next trip to IKEA to be as pleasant as possible.</a_sentence><a_sentence>So, here are some tips on how to shop the easy way at our IKEA stores!</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA stores have free parking (subject to minimum spend at Southampton and Coventry) and provide easy access for the disabled.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Everything you need to shop is available at the entrance: pencils, paper, tape measures, store guides, catalogues, shopping strollers and shopping bags.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Everything you need to know about how to shop at your local IKEA store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4193"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I check stock availability?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4284"><answer_text><a_sentence>Every effort is made to maintain the availability of items shown in the catalogue, but due to popularity and supply issues, some products may not always be available, you can check the availability of stock in your local store here.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If an item is out of stock you will have the option to leave a mobile number or email address and we will notify you when more stock arrives.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4194"><question_text><q_sentence>What online tools do you have to assist with planning?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4285"><answer_text><a_sentence>Yes, there are a number of online planning tools available for you to use to help you furnish your home, your way.</a_sentence><a_sentence>See our online planning tools</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4195"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I buy items online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4286"><answer_text><a_sentence>Most of our range is available to buy online for delivery from our distribution centre to your home address, find out more information here.Unfortunately we currently don&#39;t offer online or home-shopping in Northern Ireland and the Republic of Ireland but our stores in Belfast &#38; Dublin look forward to welcoming you.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4196"><question_text><q_sentence>What additional services do you offer to help me shop?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4287"><answer_text><a_sentence>We offer a number of services from home delivery to finance.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Find more information here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4197"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you offer any guarantees on products?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4288"><answer_text><a_sentence>We offer a range of guarantees on a number of product ranges.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can find out more information on the IKEA everyday quality guarantees.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4198"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I purchase items over the phone, for delivery or collection from store?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4289"><answer_text><a_sentence>Unfortunately it is not possible to take payments over the phone, or reserve items for collection.</a_sentence><a_sentence>When you purchase goods online they come directly from our distribution centre to your home.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4199"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I reserve an item for collection?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4290"><answer_text><a_sentence>It is not possible to reserve an item in our stores; you are able to check stock availability before visiting store using our online stock checker.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4200"><question_text><q_sentence>Store opening times and directions?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4291"><answer_text><a_sentence>Each store has their own website which includes opening times, directions and store information.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Click here to choose your favourite store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4201"><question_text><q_sentence>Is there parking when I get there?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4292"><answer_text><a_sentence>All IKEA stores have free parking (subject to minimum spend at Southampton and Coventry).</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4202"><question_text><q_sentence>What facilities do you have for people with disabilities?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4293"><answer_text><a_sentence>For our visitors with disabilities, we are pleased to offer the following services at IKEA stores: • Wheelchairs, free to use in the store.</a_sentence><a_sentence>• Assisted shopping, please go to the customer information desk in store to request this.</a_sentence><a_sentence>• Facilities for hearing impaired visitors</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4203"><question_text><q_sentence>Are your stores family friendly?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4294"><answer_text><a_sentence>Each store supplies high chairs, organic baby food, baby food warming stations, and healthy meals for children in the restaurant, play areas and nursing areas.</a_sentence><a_sentence>All our stores have a crèche facility usable for 45 minutes at a time (book in store).</a_sentence><a_sentence>Bring the family we have something for everyone.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4204"><question_text><q_sentence>Why are items sometimes out of stock?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4295"><answer_text><a_sentence>Every effort is made to maintain the availability of items shown in the catalogue, but due to popularity and supply issues, some products may not always be available.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Generally, IKEA can estimate when a product should be back in stock.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can use our online stock checker to make sure items are available before you visit.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4205"><question_text><q_sentence>Do your stores offer home delivery or van hire?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4296"><answer_text><a_sentence>Since most IKEA furniture is flat-packed, you can take your goods home today in your car and enjoy them right away.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you&#39;d prefer, IKEA can arrange home delivery at a reasonable rate, visit the home delivery desk in the Customer Service area after checkouts.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We also offer a van hire service through Europcar.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Find out more about the IKEA range of services we can offer.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4206"><question_text><q_sentence>Can you help me with assembly?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4297"><answer_text><a_sentence>Yes, you can find assembly guides next to the product description online, ask in store or call us for general help or if you would like the furniture assembled you can find more information on our services page.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4207"><question_text><q_sentence>Can someone help me plan and design rooms?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4298"><answer_text><a_sentence>Many IKEA stores offer a home decoration service if you wish to furnish an entire room or home.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Our friendly co-workers will be happy to assist you in store.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA also have online planning tools for a range of products including storage, kitchens, wardrobes and office furniture.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Our kitchen departments can also arrange a visit to your home to help design your ideal kitchen, ,a href=&#34;http://www.ikea.com/ms/en_GB/customer_service/ikea_services/kitchen_planner.html&#34;&#62;see</a_sentence><a_sentence>here for more information regarding kitchen services.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4208"><question_text><q_sentence>I&#39;ve lost something at the store - how do I get it back?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4299"><answer_text><a_sentence>For lost items, please return to the store you visited where our co-workers will be happy to help you at the customer service desk.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please note that credit cards will be destroyed after 24 hours for security purposes.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4209"><question_text><q_sentence>There seems to be a mistake on my receipt from the store.</q_sentence><q_sentence>What should I do?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4300"><answer_text><a_sentence>Please return to store with your receipt and we can investigate this for you.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you are unable to return to store please contact us.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4210"><question_text><q_sentence>Worldwide store locator</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4301"><answer_text><a_sentence>Details about IKEA stores outside of the UK can be found here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4211"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I buy online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4302"><answer_text><a_sentence>To find out how you can shop online please click here.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please note at present shopping online is only available to mainland England, Scotland and Wales.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4212"><question_text><q_sentence>Why are there products on the website that I cannot buy online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4303"><answer_text><a_sentence>The majority of the IKEA furniture range is available at Shop Online along with an increasing selection of our home accessories range.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We are planning to increase the ranges available in the future.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We do try to show as many items as possible online as you may wish to visit one of our stores for the item, and it will enable you to have the product details to hand before you visit.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Items available to purchase online have the option “Add to basket” next to them.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4213"><question_text><q_sentence>Are your prices online the same as in store?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4304"><answer_text><a_sentence>Shop Online product prices will normally be the same as store prices.</a_sentence><a_sentence>However, occasionally promotions will mean some prices can differ.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4214"><question_text><q_sentence>What if I change my mind after ordering online Online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4305"><answer_text><a_sentence>It’s fine to change your mind; you are able to cancel an order, by contacting us.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you’ve already had delivery and you’ve changed your mind, simply take it to a store or request a collection.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Full details can be found in the Shop Online returns policy.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4215"><question_text><q_sentence>Are my personal details given to third parties?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4306"><answer_text><a_sentence>We sometimes need to hire other companies to help us provide our services.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We limit the information we give them, to ensure this is only used for the fulfilment of your order.</a_sentence><a_sentence>They are strictly monitored by IKEA in order to make certain our customer privacy is always protected.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4216"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I cancel an order I placed online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4307"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA complies fully with the Distance Selling Regulations, you may cancel at any time before delivery by contacting us with your order details, after receiving your goods we understand you need time to consider your purchase, if you would like to cancel within 14 days of receiving your items, you may take the items to your nearest store with your order receipt email or contact us for collection.</a_sentence><a_sentence>This does not apply to items made to your specification.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can find more information here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4217"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I add to or change an existing order?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4308"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you need to make a change to an existing order, please call us as soon as possible.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Once your order has been confirmed any changes may delay your delivery date.</a_sentence><a_sentence>To add to an order placed in store, you would need to return to store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4218"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I order online and pick up from store?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4309"><answer_text><a_sentence>All our online products are delivered directly from our distribution centre to your home, it is not possible to collect online purchases from store, we do not offer a product reservation service in our stores.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4219"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I add assembly to my order?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4310"><answer_text><a_sentence>It is not possible to add assembly to your online order, you can visit your nearest store to arrange assembly or call us for more information.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Additional details can be found on our services page.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4220"><question_text><q_sentence>What payment methods do you accept?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4311"><answer_text><a_sentence>In store you can pay with all major credit and debit cards including: VISA, VISA Electron, MasterCard, Maestro, Delta, IKEA Home Card, IKEA Gift Card and cash.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We do not accept cheques or American Express.To view the payment methods we accept online, please click here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4221"><question_text><q_sentence>How safe are my personal details and credit card information?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4312"><answer_text><a_sentence>The security of our customers’ details is a number one priority for us.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We work with a fully integrated and secure checkout process.</a_sentence><a_sentence>All payment details are secure at all times.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can view our full privacy policy here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4222"><question_text><q_sentence>IKEA Home Card</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4313"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA Home card was a payment card previously offered by IKEA.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Existing holders may still use their cards in store.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The card was issued by contact IKANO Financial Services.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you have any questions about your card, please contact IKANO customer service at 0871 781 3045 or via email at customerservice@ikano.net.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4223"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you offer Finance options or interest free credit?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4314"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can read more about IKEA finance options here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4224"><question_text><q_sentence>When am I entitled to claim a VAT refund and what do I need to do to obtain one?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4315"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you are purchasing goods in an IKEA Store you are entitled to claim a VAT refund when you are either: • Non EU resident • Customer registered for VAT in the an EU country, other than the UK.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Non EU resident: If you are exporting purchases outside the EU you may be entitled to a VAT refund.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you are shipping the goods as freight please request an IKEA ‘VAT refunds for export outside the EU’ notice.If you are taking the goods with you as on board luggage, you must request a ‘TaxFreeWorldwide’ receipt.Customers registered for VAT in the EU not in UK: If you are dispatching purchases back to an EU country where you are registered for VAT, please request either an IKEA ‘VAT refunds for overseas businesses elsewhere in the EU’, or for Irish customers, ‘VAT refunds for businesses in the Republic of Ireland’.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please note that refunds can only be made to the persons who originally purchased the goods and cannot be made to any UK residents.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The notices will request evidence to qualify for a refund.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA must receive all necessary evidence within 3 months of the date of your purchase.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you are purchasing goods online via the IKEA website to be shipped directly abroad, then you may be able to claim back the VAT on the goods (VAT cannot be claimed for the delivery charges).</a_sentence><a_sentence>Your order confirmation email is your vat receipt.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For more information visit www.hmrc.gov.uk</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4225"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I return items?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4316"><answer_text><a_sentence>You&#39;re free to change your mind.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Return unused items in their original packaging within 90 days, together with your till receipt or copy of your online order form, for a full refund.</a_sentence><a_sentence>See our returns policy.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4226"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I return a mattress?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4317"><answer_text><a_sentence>Unless faulty you may only return a mattress for a refund within 90 days if the packaging is still on the mattress and unopened.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We do understand that you may need to try a mattress first to see if it’s comfortable that’s why you may exchange your mattress once within 90 days under our love it or exchange it offer.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4227"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I return a made to order product?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4318"><answer_text><a_sentence>Made to order products cannot be cancelled at any time as these are made specifically to your order.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The majority of made to order products are a selection from our kitchen worktop range.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We will confirm that you have ordered a made to order product and take you through the specific terms and conditions.</a_sentence><a_sentence>These products can only be returned to us if they are faulty and not fit for purpose described.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4228"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I return goods I have opened or assembled?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4319"><answer_text><a_sentence>Items can be returned to the store with your original receipt, but should be disassembled.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Depending on the condition of the items the value and method of refund would be at the discretion of the store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4229"><question_text><q_sentence>Can a different account be credited with a refund?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4320"><answer_text><a_sentence>Sorry.</a_sentence><a_sentence>A refund has to be made to the original card used for payment.</a_sentence><a_sentence>In the event that you are unable to access this account we may refund to a gift card.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4230"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you provide extra or replacement fittings?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4321"><answer_text><a_sentence>As long as the fittings have a 6 digit code in the assembly guide, we can arrange for these to be posted directly to you free of charge.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Just click here to fill out a parts request form.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you no longer have the assembly guide, copies can be found in the product description on the website, or for older products click here</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4231"><question_text><q_sentence>I’m missing part of a product I’ve just purchased.</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4322"><answer_text><a_sentence>Please take your receipt and copy of the assembly guide showing the piece that is missing to store and we will replace this for you, if this part has a 6 digit code on the assembly guide we can arrange for these to be posted directly to you free of charge.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Just click here to fill out a parts request form.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4232"><question_text><q_sentence>The product I’ve purchased has a faulty or damaged part.</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4323"><answer_text><a_sentence>You only need to take the faulty part to store with your receipt and we will exchange this for you.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Alternatively you may return the whole product for a replacement or full refund.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you damaged the item yourself and swiped your FAMILY card at the till, you may be covered by FAMILY card insurance.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4233"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I get help with assembly?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4324"><answer_text><a_sentence>All our products come with detailed instructions, if you need more help we do have instructional videos for our most popular products here, or if you go to store you can arrange for an assembly company, click here for more information.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4234"><question_text><q_sentence>Missing Assembly Guide</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4325"><answer_text><a_sentence>Copies can be found in the product description on the website.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you are still unable to locate the assembly guide, please contact us with either the article number or if possible email pictures of the item and we will do our best to locate them for you.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4235"><question_text><q_sentence>Faulty items, under guarantee</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4326"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA offers a generous guarantee policy.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Guarantees can be found in the back of the catalogue or by clicking here.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you do notice a problem with any product within the first year of purchase or within the full guarantee period, please return the item to store or email pictures and a description of the fault.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please include proof of the original purchase from IKEA.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4236"><question_text><q_sentence>Where do I find information about product recalls?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4327"><answer_text><a_sentence>For information about product recalls and safety alerts please visit our press page here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4237"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you deliver?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4328"><answer_text><a_sentence>Yes we can deliver, you can either visit one our stores where you may be able to use our home delivery service arrange next day delivery, or you may purchase online and use our online delivery service to have your items delivered directly to your home.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4238"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I get a faster delivery?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4329"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you are ordering online, the estimated delivery date is the earliest date we can deliver as the items come from our distribution centre.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you visit store, our home delivery service may be able to offer you next day delivery.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4239"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you do international shipping?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4330"><answer_text><a_sentence>Our online shopping service is only able to deliver items to mainland UK; however we can deliver to a shipping agent if you specify them as the delivery address when you order.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4240"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I choose a delivery time?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4331"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you arrange our home delivery in store, they will contact you one hour before they are due to arrive, they deliver between 7am and 8pm.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For online orders or orders sent from our distribution centre you can find full delivery information here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4241"><question_text><q_sentence>Will I be able to order online and then pick up in the store?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4332"><answer_text><a_sentence>Our online orders are only able to be delivered directly from our distribution centre to your home.</a_sentence><a_sentence>It is not possible to order and reserve in store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4242"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I order delivery to a different name or address?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4333"><answer_text><a_sentence>Yes, as long as the delivery address is in mainland UK.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4243"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I track my delivery?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4334"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you have purchased online you will be able to use our order tracking you will need your order number, post code and the email address you gave when the order was placed.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For deliveries booked in store we will agree a delivery day, then call you one hour before we are due to deliver.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4244"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I change my delivery date?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4335"><answer_text><a_sentence>The original estimated date you receive is the earliest date we can get your order to you.</a_sentence><a_sentence>It may be possible to deliver it at a slightly later date, on a day that’s more convenient to you.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please contact us as soon as possible if you require a later date.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4245"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I tell you about delivery restrictions?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4336"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you think we may have difficulty accessing your property, please click here for more information.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4246"><question_text><q_sentence>Do you do next day delivery?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4337"><answer_text><a_sentence>When you visit store the majority of our deliveries will be within 48 hours, and normally next day subject to availability, and the distance you live from the store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4247"><question_text><q_sentence>How much does delivery cost?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4338"><answer_text><a_sentence>When you shop online, you can see the cost of delivery before ordering by placing your items in the basket, adding your postcode and press calculate.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For our home delivery service from store, please choose the store you wish to visit from the link on this page.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4248"><question_text><q_sentence>What do I do if I have something missing from my delivery?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4339"><answer_text><a_sentence>You should contact the delivery company as soon as possible, their contact details will be on your delivery paperwork, alternatively you can contact us.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4249"><question_text><q_sentence>What is IKEA FAMILY?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4340"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA FAMILY is the IKEA loyalty programme.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA FAMILY is open to everyone, and it’s free to join.</a_sentence><a_sentence>With an IKEA FAMILY card you get discounts on selected home furnishing products, food products and services.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We also hold member only events in-stores such as free home furnishing workshops/seminars and previews of new ranges.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Find out more.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4250"><question_text><q_sentence>How can I become an IKEA FAMILY member?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4341"><answer_text><a_sentence>It is free to sign up and you can start using the benefits the same day.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can sign up, in store, via a paper application, in one of the IKEA FAMILY kiosks or online today.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You will get a temporary card on registration; your plastic card will be sent home to you within 2-4 weeks of registration, your temporary card entitles you to all the benefits until the plastic card arrives.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4251"><question_text><q_sentence>What do I do if I want to shop at IKEA before my card arrives?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4342"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can always print out a temporary card, either online or in store at a FAMILY kioskYou need to show a card, plastic or temporary, at time of purchase to qualify for an IKEA FAMILY offer in store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4252"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I add an existing purchase to my FAMILY card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4343"><answer_text><a_sentence>To qualify for any offers you need to swipe your card at the time of purchase, it is not possible to add an existing purchase at a later date.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4253"><question_text><q_sentence>What do I do if I have lost my card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4344"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can request a new card; in store, online via your FAMILY account or contact us.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can print out a temporary card from either your online account or in store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4254"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I make changes to my FAMILY card details, or cancel my account?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4345"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can update any of your details such as name, address, contact details, marketing preferences and home interests online via your FAMILY account.</a_sentence><a_sentence>To cancel, simply log in and choose the option to cancel at the bottom the FAMILY account page.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Alternatively you may contact us.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4255"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I log in to my online account?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4346"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can log in here.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You need to have an email address registered with us in order to access your online IKEA FAMILY account.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4256"><question_text><q_sentence>I’ve forgotten my email or password:</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4347"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can retrieve the email address attached to your account or a lost password by selecting “password help” from the log in page.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4257"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I sign up to a workshop, seminar or event?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4348"><answer_text><a_sentence>All events are listed by store here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4258"><question_text><q_sentence>Can you tell me more about the free product insurance?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4349"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA FAMILY members benefit from free product insurance, against any accidental damage on the way home or whilst assembling.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The insurance is valid on any purchase and not just items with an IKEA FAMILY price.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The IKEA FAMILY card must be swiped at time of purchase to insure the products.</a_sentence><a_sentence>To claim on your insurance please come to store within 90 days of the date of purchase with the item, your FAMILY card and your receipt.Insurance can only be claimed in store, not by contacting Customer Services by phone, email or online.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Terms and conditions.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4259"><question_text><q_sentence>What are the FAMILY general terms and conditions?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4350"><answer_text><a_sentence>Full terms and Conditions can be found here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4260"><question_text><q_sentence>How is my data being used?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4351"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA Ltd will safeguard any information provided.</a_sentence><a_sentence>More information can be found here.</a_sentence><a_sentence>More info can be found here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4261"><question_text><q_sentence>Is there credit connected to the IKEA FAMILY card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4352"><answer_text><a_sentence>No there is not credit connected to the card.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA does not currently offer a credit card.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4262"><question_text><q_sentence>Is IKEA FAMILY card the same as IKEA Home Card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4353"><answer_text><a_sentence>No, the IKEA Home Card is a credit card previously offered to IKEA customers.</a_sentence><a_sentence>These credit cards are no longer issued, but are still valid as payment in-store.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4263"><question_text><q_sentence>Who do I contact about my IKEA Home Card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4354"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA Home card is issued by IKANO Financial Services.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you have any questions about your card, contact IKANO customer service at 0871 781 3045 or via email at customerservice@ikano.net.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4264"><question_text><q_sentence>What is the IKEA catalogue?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4355"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA catalogue is produced in 30 languages and more than 210 million copies and delivered to homes in 44 countries.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The catalogue offers more than just a glimpse at the diverse IKEA product range.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You&#39;ll discover new affordable solutions and creative approaches to help inspire home furnishing ideas for better living.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For the best possible ideas and inspiration the online catalogue comes with augmented reality.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4265"><question_text><q_sentence>How can I get a copy of the IKEA catalogue?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4356"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA catalogue is mass-distributed annually in the area around each IKEA store.</a_sentence><a_sentence>If you did not receive this year&#39;s catalogue, stop by the IKEA store near you for a free copy.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Alternatively, you can view the whole catalogue online Download our latest catalogue, or view it on the IKEA catalogue app for your smart phone available from your app store.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Unfortunately we are unable to post copies.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4266"><question_text><q_sentence>When does the new catalogue come out?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4357"><answer_text><a_sentence>The annual catalogue is distributed in August/September of each year and is valid for a full year.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Prices are guaranteed not to increase while the catalogue is valid.</a_sentence><a_sentence>In it you can discover our furnishings, accessories and room settings along with detailed information on materials, colours, sizes, product care, prices and additional content accessible through your mobile phone.</a_sentence><a_sentence>That way you can plan your next visit to IKEA all from the comfort of your own home!</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4267"><question_text><q_sentence>How environmentally friendly is the IKEA catalogue?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4358"><answer_text><a_sentence>Our catalogues are printed on totally chlorine-free paper and contain at least 10-15% post-consumer waste.</a_sentence><a_sentence>No rainforest or old-growth fibres are used.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The pre-press process is 100% digital, which means no film is used and none of the associated chemicals.</a_sentence><a_sentence>No optical brighteners are used on the paper.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4268"><question_text><q_sentence>What settings or software do I need on my computer to view the IKEA site?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4359"><answer_text><a_sentence>In order to view the IKEA site you need a normal modern web browser like Chrome, Firefox, Internet Explorer or Safari.Both Chrome and Firefox are automatically updated on a frequent basis and IKEA recommend users to always upgrade.For Internet Explorer we support version 8 to 11, and for Safari we support version 5 to 7.If you are using a Smartphone or tablet with Android, both the Chrome browser and the built in Android browser will work since Android version 2.3.If you are using an iPhone or iPad with Safari we support version 5 to 7.The IKEA site is built to support a wide range of browsers and other modern browsers than those mentioned above should work fine too, even if we are not actively testing them in our development.One</a_sentence><a_sentence>exception that we know of, is that Internet Explorer 7 and earlier will not support all features.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4269"><question_text><q_sentence>What information is collected about me when I visit the site?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4360"><answer_text><a_sentence>We do not require any information to obtain access to any part of our site, unless specifically stated.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We may ask for specific information in order to provide a service to you, such as our FAMILY card.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Information requested may include name, title, company, address, e-mail address, and phone number.</a_sentence><a_sentence>We do anonymously track traffic patterns using cookies, in order to measure site performance and make improvements.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Cookies are small pieces of information stored on your computer that are read by the browser.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4270"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I find all IKEA products on this site?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4361"><answer_text><a_sentence>This site features hundreds of IKEA products as a way of demonstrating the breadth and depth of our product range; however, this is only a small portion of IKEA’s complete product range.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Each store carries a much larger selection.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Be sure to visit your local IKEA store for a look at our full selection.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4271"><question_text><q_sentence>I’ve forgotten my account email or password</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4362"><answer_text><a_sentence>You can retrieve the email address attached to your account or a lost password by selecting “password help” from the log in page.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4272"><question_text><q_sentence>Who owns the IKEA concept?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4363"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA retailing, with its Swedish roots, is based on a franchise system.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Inter IKEA Systems B.V., located in Delft, The Netherlands, is the owner and franchisor of the IKEA Concept.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA stores are operated by a number of different franchisees in 29 countries.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4273"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I distribute IKEA products?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4364"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA experience is more than just products, it is a retail concept.</a_sentence><a_sentence>For the concept to work, it is necessary to have all aspects in place.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Therefore, IKEA products are sold only in IKEA stores franchised by Inter IKEA Systems B.V.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4274"><question_text><q_sentence>How can I become a franchisee?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4365"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA products are sold solely in stores operating the IKEA Retail System--franchised by Inter IKEA Systems B.V. of The Netherlands.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Franchises are granted by Inter IKEA Systems B.V. as part of a detailed expansion plan.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Serious applicants are carefully researched and evaluated and franchises are granted only to companies and/or individuals with strong financial backing and a proven record in retail.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Please visit our franchisor site for more information.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4275"><question_text><q_sentence>What is the IKEA Group?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4366"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA Group is a private group of companies owned by a charitable foundation in The Netherlands.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The IKEA Group is active in developing, purchasing, distributing and selling IKEA products.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The IKEA group is the biggest group of franchisees operating over 100 IKEA stores.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The Management Services to the IKEA Group are provided by IKEA International A/S in Humlebaek, Denmark.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4276"><question_text><q_sentence>What is the IKEA business idea?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4367"><answer_text><a_sentence>The IKEA business idea is: &#34;We shall offer a wide range of well-designed, functional home furnishing products at prices so low that as many people as possible will be able to afford them.&#34;</a_sentence><a_sentence>More information about the IKEA group can be found here.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4277"><question_text><q_sentence>How can I find out about job opportunities within IKEA?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4368"><answer_text><a_sentence>If you are out-going, dedicated, customer-service orientated and interested in working as part of a team, contact the IKEA store near you for possible openings.</a_sentence><a_sentence>It is also possible to view openings at your local store by visiting the job section within our website.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4278"><question_text><q_sentence>How does IKEA approach environmental issues?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4369"><answer_text><a_sentence>We&#39;re working to create a better everyday life for the many people.</a_sentence><a_sentence>This includes doing what we can to help create a world where we take better care of our environment.</a_sentence><a_sentence>You can find out more information in the People and Planet section of the website.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4279"><question_text><q_sentence>Where are IKEA products manufactured</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4370"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA has more than 1200 furniture suppliers around the world as well as 100 food suppliers and 275 suppliers of transport.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The five countries that supply most goods and services to IKEA are China, Poland, Italy, Germany and Sweden.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The profile of our well-designed and high quality range is distinctively Swedish/Scandinavian.</a_sentence><a_sentence>The low price is literally built into the production and the flat packs facilitate a rational distribution, self-service and immediate take-away.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4280"><question_text><q_sentence>What is your registered UK business address and VAT number?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4371"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA Limited is a company registered in England with its registered office at Witan Gate House 500-600 Witan Gate West Milton Keynes MK9 1SH and company number 01986283.</a_sentence><a_sentence>Our VAT number is 527773320.</a_sentence><a_sentence>IKEA Limited is licensed to sell under the IKEA brand name by Inter IKEA Systems B.V., a company registered in the Netherlands.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4281"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I use my gift card online?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4372"><answer_text><a_sentence>IKEA Gift cards can be used to make a purchase online as long as they have a scratch off pin number on the back of the card, all cards issued after October 2013 will have this pin number.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4282"><question_text><q_sentence>How long is my gift card valid for?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4373"><answer_text><a_sentence>Gift cards have no expiry date.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4283"><question_text><q_sentence>Can I use gift cards in other Countries?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4374"><answer_text><a_sentence>Please see here for a list of countries that accept UK Gift Cards.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question><question id="Q4284"><question_text><q_sentence>How do I purchase a gift card?</q_sentence></question_text><answer id="A4375"><answer_text><a_sentence>Gift cards may be purchased in store or online.</a_sentence></answer_text><num_votes>1</num_votes></answer></question></lecture></course>